<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data date-time-format="iso8601" >

	<event 
			start="1972-01" end="1982-01" isDuration="true"
			title="FORTRAN"
			classname="skill_event">
		Started coding with punched cards and moved on to the latest
		technology -- online timesharing (with a teletype and modem).
		First useful applications developed in FORTRA.
		Also learned the importance of good design to support
		maintenance and future requirements 
		(spaghetti code can be very hard to digest later).
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="1973-01" end="1986-01" isDuration="true"
			title="BASIC"
			classname="skill_event">
			A PDP 11/40, a teletype, 8K of RAM, and paper tape. What else could you want?
			Once the PC appeared, found I could make a living coding.
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="1983-01" end="2003-01" isDuration="true"
			title="C"
			classname="skill_event">
		In the beginning it was just me and the white book (K&amp;R);
		but a door to everything. Spent most of career writing C, but it has
		been a while (except for the occasional C# now).
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="1983-05" end="2008-01" isDuration="true"
			title="UNIX, BSD, Linux"
			classname="skill_tech">
		First love? Maybe. It is still my favorite development platform.
		Even exiled to the land of Windows I keep the GNU tools available
		so that I can run the shell for command line work. You never know
		when you might need a quick AWK script. 
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="1984-03" end="2015-01" isDuration="true"
			title="PC-DOS, Windows ..."
			classname="skill_tech">
		The platform I love to hate. Have still not escaped.
		Can configure a server and IIS -- but I don't have to
		enjoy it.
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="1989-01" end="2015-01" isDuration="true"
			title="Oracle"
			classname="skill_event">
		There have been a couple other relational DBs in my life,
		but Oracle is still the main one. It's all about the SQL.
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="1994-01" end="2006-05" isDuration="true"
			title="Smalltalk"
			classname="skill_event">
		This is where objects became real. The Smalltalk world was
		a little off the main stream, but it was the basis for learning
		proper OO design, patterns, and iterative development.
		The instant gratification was good too.
		(Java owes Smalltalk a lot.)
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="1996-04" end="2015-01" isDuration="true"
			title="Java"
			classname="skill_event">
		Things have come a long way since animated Duke
		applets in a browser. Java is my main coding expression these days.
		I can build a UI if required (it may not be pretty), 
		but backend services and integration are where I like to work.
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="1996-10" end="2015-01" isDuration="true"
			title="HTML, CSS, Javascript, XML/XSL, AJAX"
			classname="skill_event">
		Confession time here -- when I first saw a website in Mozilla -- I thought
		the technology was a fad. Now I'm posting a resume in HTML. Since then I've
		touched it all: Javascript hosted in the page with jQuery and server side 
		applications using everything from plain JSP to complete UI frameworks (Vaadin).
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="2009-07" end="2015-01" isDuration="true"
			title="web services (SOAP, REST)"
			classname="skill_event">
		Have developed new web services and extended existing ones using
		a variety of frameworks (Axis 1/2, Apache CXF, and even Microsoft WCF).
		While most of my work has been service development there have been a couple
		client applications in Java and Windows .NET.
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>
	<event 
			start="2011-08" end="2015-01" isDuration="true"
			title="C#, .NET"
			classname="skill_event">
		VisualStudio is still not my favorite IDE, but it does work.
		So my old C skills have slightly resurrected.
		&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;br/&gt;
	</event>

</data>
